IBM Manuals 5341
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
IBM Manuals
1939-1942
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Business Machines Corporation (IBM)
5341
1.5 cubic feet
1.5 linear ft.
Training manuals, records (documents).
This collection consists of Publications of the International Business Machine Corporation.
5599262
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 02, 2005
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 11, 2019
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of Publications of the International Business Machine Corporation.
Included are training manuals for factory employees and customers.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
International Business Machines Corporation.
5599262
- IBM Employee Training - Blue Print Reading, 1939-1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Manual of Instruction, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    By Educational Department. Item is in English.
- IBM Employee Training - Drilling, 1939-1942; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Manual of Instruction, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
- IBM Employee Training - Electricity, 1939-1942; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Manual of Instruction: Elementary Electricity, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
- IBM Employee Training - Foundry Practice, 1939-1942; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Foundry Practice, Forging Practice, Grinding, Die Casting, Heat, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
- IBM Employee Training - International Electric Card-Operated Sorting Machine, 1939-1942; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: The International Electric Card-Operated Sorting Machine, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
- IBM Employee Training - Modern Drilling Practice, 1939-1942; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Modern Drilling Practice, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
- IBM Employee Training - Modern Grinding Practice, 1939-1942; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Shop Mathematics, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
- IBM Employee Training - Shop Mathematics, 1939-1942; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Tool Planning Practice, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
- IBM Employee Training - Tool Grinding Machines, 1939-1942; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Modern Grinding Practice, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
- IBM Employee Training - Tool Planning Practice, 1939-1942; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
- IBM User Manual - Machine Methods of Accounting, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Managerial Accounting by Machine Methods, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
    By Educational Department. General Office Procedures. Item is in English.
- IBM User Manual - Managerial Accounting by Machine Methods, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Machine Methods of Accounting, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)